Jose Laurito Software Engineer

703-457-0021 | Portfolio | github.com/iigolauritog3 | jigolaurito@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/iose-laurito

SUMMARY

Adaptable Software Engineer with culinary expertise, skilled in **JavaScript**, **Python**, and **React.JS**. Contributed to notable projects like "**Break Buddy**" and "**Matrimoni**" at **Co.Lab**. Combining precision with innovation, I also possess a basic understanding of **computer hardware components**. Driven by a passion for innovation, I excel in collaborative, **Agile environments**, actively participating in **code reviews** and implementing best practices for **continuous integration and deployment**.

SKILLS

Languages/Database: JavaScript, Python, HTML5, CSS, Dart, MongoDB - NoSQL

Frameworks/Libraries: React.js, Axios, Redux Toolkit, Flutter, Tailwind CSS, Express.js, Node.js, Mongoose, EJS, Flask, Bootstrap, JQuery

Tools/DevOps: Github, Visual Studios Code, Google Docs, Slack, Vite.js, Postman, Figma, Android Studios Certifications: Coding Temple - Full-Stack Software Engineer (JavaScript, Python, CSS, HTML5, Flask, React.js, SQL), Co.Lab - Software Developer

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Co.Lab (Remote) - Break Buddy & Matrimoni

09/2023 - 04/2024

- Developed and contributed to "Break Buddy" and "Matrimoni" projects
- Utilized React.js, Tailwind CSS, and Material-UI for seamless and visually appealing user experiences.
- Deployed "Break Buddy" on Vercel, actively involved in CI/CD processes for efficient updates.
- Conducted **code reviews**, ensuring high-quality code and adherence to coding standards.
- Implemented version control using GitHub and collaborated in Agile development methodologies.
- Utilized Firebase for secure user authentication in applications.
- Gained hands-on experience in full-stack development and responsive web design techniques.

Restaurant/Hotel Chef - Marriott Magnificent Mile, Chicago IL

08/2019 - Present

- Assisted with the development of full, tasting and special event menus to meet all establishment needs and maintain strong customer levels outlined by Marriott Brand which resulted in high customer satisfaction scores.
- Plated every dish with attractive flair to meet strict restaurant standards and maintain a stellar business reputation.

EDUCATION

Coding Temple - Chicago, IL

02/2023 -04/2023

- Full-Stack Software Engineering

De La Salle - College of Saint Benilde - Manila Philippines

04/2010 - 07/2016

- Bachelor of Science in Hotel, Restaurant & Institution Management (Major in Culinary Arts)

PROJECTS

Break Buddy - January 2023 - April 2024

Technologies: JavaScript, Tailwind, CSS, HTML, Firebase, React.js

- Developed a web app addressing challenges in remote work, enhancing social breaks for remote workers.
- Transformed breaks into social moments, promoting accountability, sociability, and healthier work habits.
- Implemented features such as a **shared calendar**, **activity options**, **online meetups**, and **calendar integration**.
- Focused on improving mental, social, and physical well-being within the remote work environment.

Matrimoni - September 2023 - November 2023

Technologies: JavaScript, Tailwind, CSS, HTML, Firebase, React.js

- Produced an application that simplifies the wedding planning experience for couples. With a **venue search** feature, users can refine their venue search based on their preferences.
- Enabled real-time updates of the **pie chart** using a JavaScript library, providing users with immediate feedback on their budget distribution as they input and adjust their spending.

 Worked with UI frameworks and libraries such as Tailwind CSS and Material-UI for efficient and visually appealing designs.

SubTrackr App - April 17-21, 2023

Technologies: Python, Bootstrap, CSS, Flask, HTML, SQLAlchemy, Jinja, REST API, Canva

- In 5 days, I created and built a Flask-based web application called **SubTrackr**. It is a web application that allows users to store their monthly/annual subscriptions to the app with its main purpose to enable users to view all their subscriptions and memberships on a single screen, it allows users to stay informed about upcoming dues and make timely payments to avoid late fees and overdrafts.
- Built a website framework with Flask and wrote Python script to create forms, routes and models.
- Operated a **SQLAlchemy database** in **Flask** to store, create and delete user data and post inventory.
- Constructed the website layout using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap to give each page a uniform & branded look
- Incorporated user authentication and authorization with Flask-Login.